

PROFILE

Degree in Electronic Engineering and Telecommunications at University of Aveiro with extensive experience in multinationals of Telecommunications and Software sector. Proven responsibility in the management of projects of various dimensions, management of outsourcing teams and architecture of technical solutions. Currently in development and execution of own business with commercial, technical, management and human resources training functions. Resilient professional, with a great sense of responsibility and easy adaptation to new challenges, environments, cultures and technologies

CONTACTS:

TELEPHONE: +351 912 124 320

EMAIL: paulojorgepeixoto@hotmail.com

Portugal / Lisbon Area

SITE: www.linkedin.com/in/paulo-peixoto-549a22

Paulo Peixoto

Self-Business Entrepreneur / Account Manager / System engineer

ACADEMIC EDUCATION

Aveiro University

Degree in Electronic engineering and telecommunications in 1999

Project Management Institute

Project Management Professional in 2005

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Main Functions	Business area	Role
Entrepreneur / Systems Engineer (9 years)	Systems Information, IT equipment and related services	Development and execution of own businesses.
Account Manager (5 years)	Systems Information, selling support Services	Customer Management, negotiation, public tenders, development of business plans.
	Telecommunications (TETRA, WiMAX, PtP, MPtP, Public Safety Networks)	Customer Management, negotiation, public tenders, business plan development
Project manager (4 years)	Telecommunications (GSM, 3G, PtP)	Management of several projects simultaneously, pre- sales and support for the development of commercial proposals
		Project management, negotiation with service providers, development of technical solutions
System engineer (3 years)	Telecommunications (GSM)	Creation and management of implementation plans, negotiation with service providers, development and execution of technical solutions
		Operation and Maintenance of telecommunications networks

PPSI Unipessoal Lda / Entrepreneur and Systems Engineer August 2011 - Presente

Development and execution of own business as general Manager at PPSI Unipessoal Lda. Sale of IT equipment's and related services. Provision of maintenance services for small companies and private market. Microelectronic repair laboratory offering services for computer stores.

Oracle / Account Manager

February 2010 - July 2011

Team Leader of the support renewal team in Portugal. Responsible for managing Support Contracts for the largest Public and Private Sector Customers, reporting to the Manager of Portugal and Spain. Development of relationships with other functional areas, improving and streamlining processes and KPIs monitoring and reporting.

Motorola / Account Manager

June 2006 - December 2009

Account Manager in the Government and Public Safety team reporting to the sales director. Responsible for business development and preparation of proposals for a wide portfolio of clients, namely government institutions and large local companies, with the development of the procedures necessary for public procurement and responses to public tenders' specifications. Main goals:

- Development of proposals for the national SIRESP network in terms of infrastructure and in terms of TETRA terminals (Examples: Proposal for Metro de Lisboa and for the Ministry of Internal Administration)
- Development of proposals for Portugal and Angola for point-to-point and multipoint communications networks in various technologies, namely FWA, OFDM and WiMAX.

Motorola / Project Manager

February 2004 - May 2006

Responsible for the management of projects of various dimensions, always accumulating responsibility for the total survey of customer requirements, planning and managing field operations, as well as the relationship with the customer and suppliers, reporting to the director operations.

Main responsibilities and objectives achieved:

- Total swap of Lucent equipment on the TMN network. Replacement of 239
 GSM stations in the Interior North of Portugal. Dimensioning of the technical
 solution, inspection actions of the subcontracted companies. Full
 coordination of field operations and interface with the end customer.
- Project Manager for the expansion of TMN's UMTS network in Madeira.
 Construction and implementation of the Project in a fast deployment scenario for a network of 50 radio stations, with a total duration of 3 months.
- Responsible for operation and maintenance contract for TMN's GSM network in Madeira Island under a full turnkey contract, inspection activities of subcontractors work and the management of the radio and infrastructure network KPIs.

Motorola / Rollout Coordinator

March 2000 - January 2004

Rollout Coordinator of Motorola Portugal for the TMN account. Administration and coordination of subcontracted services. Management of implementation plans and equipment. Elaboration of weekly work plans. Interface with customers and subcontracted companies. Preparation and optimization of work procedures. Technical support to Field Engineers in the Motorola equipment integration in the TMN network.

Motorola / Systems Engineer

August 1999 - February 2000

Integration of Motorola equipment in the GSM TMN network and operations and maintenance activities in a Full Turnkey contract for a South Lisbon area and in central Islands of Azores for TMN Account.

TRAINING

Quality training courses at Motorola University, namely in the Digital Six Sigma quality system and Motorola's Green Belt program.

Extensive training plan on Motorola GSM / UMTS / TETRA technologies

Training in the areas of leadership, behavioral management, team management and sales at Motorola University.

Several Oracle University courses for Oracle standards and procedures, highlighting Advanced Deal Management and Sun Hardware for Support.